# **Mattia Righetti**

☑ mattiarighetti@outlook.com 🌐 mattrighetti.com 🦃 mattrighetti 🛅 mattia-righetti

# What I Do

## **Software Engineering**

- · Develop backend systems that are reliable and perform well and are easy to maintain. I have experience with different languages, lately I have mostly worked with Go and Rust and different databases. I have experience in working with microservices.
- I develop apps for macOS and iOS, mostly as a hobby.
- · I contribute to open source projects, I am an active maintainer in the Network Health team at the Tor Project where I take care of NetworkStatusAPIs
- I develop CI/CD pipelines on GitHub and GitLab to help testing, benchmarking and deploying services in a safe way.
- I help with frontend: I have worked with React, TS, JS and HTML/CSS in a lot of personal projects.

# **Experience**

#### **Anthropos**

Backend Engineer | May 2023 - now

- · Worked with GraphQL mutations, queries and schema resolvers. Helped with the migration from REST APIs to GraphQL for our backend system. Implemented both REST APIs and GraphQL APIs in conjuction with a ORM framework.
- Improved and worked on Anthropos microservices that were responsible for job simulations orchestrated with AI, implemented GraphQL servers for each microservice and bridged their features with the pre-existing RPC APIs
- Integrated Stripe's payment processing capabilities with our backend infrastructure
- · Setup Apollo Router using graph federation, established a standardized way to version and deploy the supergraph service as microservices changed their GraphQL schema
- Lead development of the Anthropos iOS application
- Redesigned and enhanced data parsing and autofill capabilities of Anthropos chrome extension using React. Improved user experience and made it easier for customers to efficiently manage and automate job applications

#### Amazon

SDE Intern | June 2022 - Nov 2022

- · Developed and optimized new backend APIs that automated most of the interactions that other teams had with our service, making it faster, more efficient and available 24/7.
- · Designed and developed a web application to showcase our team's APIs and services which made the onboarding process for stakeholders smooth and enjoyable.
- Deployed and maintained OSRM service to support team services that needed to scale and had internal API limitations.
- Data pipelines management and data manipulation with Apache Airflow, AWS Glue and AWS ECR. Improved parallelisms of data transformation pipelines.
- Setup multiple pipeline to manage CI/CD of team services with the use of AWS CDK and AWS CloudFormation.

#### Politecnico di Milano

Fullstack Engineer | Jun 2018 - Sep 2021

• Designed and maintained database to support department required features.

- Developed web application that made interaction with the database more intuitive and quick for all the students of the department.
- Developed backend REST APIs used by the web application to interact with the database.
- VPS administration and maintenance including domain registration and networking setup.

### Education

I have a BSc and a MSc in Computer Science, graduating from Politecnicno di Milano, IT.

# **About Me**

My interest in software started with Android phones, I was 13 and with my HTC Desire I had a very active presence on XDA forum (my account is still there indeed matt95) trying out custom ROMs and helping others with different guides that I wrote with my poor english. Not long after that, I built my first computer all by myself. With that, I started programming a couple of months later. Java was my very first language, I remember reading the Java 7 book during biology classes in high school. Curiosity has been driving me from that day forward.